恶魔城
第四季 第２集
‎我还有一些线索
I have some more material.
‎看上去你必须查明并确定
It seems you will have to identify and secure
他死亡的准确位置
the precise location of his death.
‎我是说 ‎地板上的准确位置
By which I mean the exact spot on the floor.
‎告诉瓦尼 有确切证据表明
And tell Varney there is definitely evidence
塔哥维斯特的宫廷手里有一面传送镜
of a transmission mirror in the possession of the court at Targoviste.
‎我在设法追查更多的信息
I'm working to track down more information.
‎卡米拉的私人珍藏
From Carmilla's private stock.
‎现在 给我看看你说过的地狱地图
Now show me the map of hell you told me about,
‎不然我就告诉她 ‎你对她的鞋动了手脚
or I'll tell her what you've been doing with her shoes.
‎早上好
Morning.
‎晚上好
Evening.
‎该死
Fuck!
‎你做坏了
You broke it.
‎这些钢胚有一半是坏的
Half these billets are bad.
‎你的吸血鬼铁匠没有按我的要求做
Your vampire blacksmiths didn't follow my specifications.
‎蹩脚的工匠总是归罪于吸血鬼
A bad workman always blames his vampires.
‎你没有别的事可做吗
Don't you have anything better to do?
‎现在没有
Not right now.
‎斯崔格和莫拉娜离开好几个星期了
Striga and Morana have been away for weeks,
‎勘查将要吞并的领土
surveying the territories to be annexed.
‎卡米拉在画地图
Carmilla is drawing maps.
‎看来 一切事情都需要外交的‎时代
It seems the time when diplomacy
似乎已经过去了
was required for anything has passed.
所以你觉得无聊
Ah, so you're bored.
不 ‎你是在担心
No. You're worried.
‎闭嘴
Shush.
‎丽诺尔 她们在排挤你吗
Lenore, are they sidelining you?
‎她们没有…
They're not...
‎不是那样的
It's not like that.
‎至少她们不会那样想
Or, at least, they wouldn't think of it like that.
‎我们的生活进入了新阶段
Our lives have entered a new phase.
‎外交 谈判
Diplomacy, negotiations,
这些已经成为了历史
these are things of the past now.
‎也让你成为了历史
Which makes you a thing of the past,
这让你很困扰
and that is bothering you.
‎听着...
Look...
‎卡米拉计划给我们争取
Carmilla's plan buys us security
‎未来几百年的保障
for hundreds of years.
‎我是经历过战争的孩子 赫克托
I'm a child of war, Hector.
‎我就出生在这样的城堡里
I was born in a castle like this.
‎英国士兵嘴里叼着刀子
My parents died when English soldiers
爬上马桶滑槽 杀死了我父母
climbed up the toilet chutes with knives in their teeth.
‎我在五岁前见惯了战争
I'd seen enough war before I was five years old,
‎此后的生活也没有变好
and life didn't get better after that.
‎但我绝不会心安理得地认为
But I will never be comfortable
‎结束战争最好的方法就是
with the idea that the best way to end war
‎杀掉大部分人 把其他人关进牢房
is to kill most of the people and cage the rest.
‎你是外交官
Well, you are a diplomat.
‎要是你不做那把该死的锤子
Well, none of this will matter
‎就不会这么闹心了
if you don't make that bloody hammer.
‎为什么你不能像巫师一样
Why can't you just wave your fingers like a wizard
‎挥动手指就能起死回生
to raise the dead, or whatever?
‎锻造师借助工具来工作
The forgemaster works through an instrument.
‎这可能是我听过的
That may be the worst justification
‎男人要握着小鸡鸡最差劲的借口了
for a man holding his penis that I've ever heard.
‎我的天啊
Oh, my God.
‎我都200岁了
And I am 200 years old.
‎听着...
Look...
我是锻造师
I am a forgemaster.
‎这名字不是我发明的 好吗
I didn't invent the name, all right?
‎他们就是这么叫我们的
That's just what they call us.
‎通过工具才能把魔法集中起来施展
And the magic has to be focused through an instrument,
‎就像用笛子吹气一样
like breath being pushed through a flute.
这个解释没什么用
This isn't getting any better.
‎我需要该死的锤子 这个解释行吗
I need the bloody hammer. Is that better?
‎那就用该死的锤子啊
So use a bloody hammer.
‎这里肯定有上千把该死的锤子
There must be a thousand bloody hammers around here.
‎不 一定要特别的锤子
No, it's got to be special.
‎你的特别的锤子
Your special hammer.
‎你够了吗
Would you stop?
‎一定要从头做起
It has to be made from scratch,
用非常特别的方式
in a very particular way,
‎否则就不管用
or else it won't work.
‎就像没有孔的笛子
Like a flute with no holes.
‎没错
Right.
供手指摆弄
For fingering.
‎你够了吗
Would you stop?
‎所以要是你搞砸了 就什么都锻造不出来
So when you blow it, nothing comes out.
‎天啊 你这女人
Good god, woman.
‎我很无聊 吓唬你找点乐子
I'm bored, and it's fun to horrify you.
满足我吧
Indulge me.
‎然后想想怎么告诉卡米拉
And think of something to tell Carmilla.
她会很生气的
She's getting very cross.
‎亲爱的 真遗憾
Oh, dear. How sad.
‎别在意
Never mind.
‎说真的
Seriously.
‎你应该已经做了好几周魔法锤了
You've supposedly been making your magic hammer for weeks.
‎你就不能做个简单点的工具
Couldn't you make something simpler?
‎棍子 硬币 或者别的东西
A stick, or a coin, or something?
‎我们都用不同的工具
We all use different things.
‎艾萨克用的是一把刀
Isaac used a knife.
‎锤子更适合我
A hammer works better for me.
‎好吧 那就快点做出来
Well, make it work faster.
‎要是卡米拉发脾气
If Carmilla loses her temper,
‎我没办法站在你前面帮你挡很久
I won't be able to stand in front of you for long.
‎你有站在我前面帮我挡吗
You'd stand in front of me?
‎已经挡了好几周了
I've been doing it for weeks.
‎嗯 好吧
Huh. Yes.
好吧 可不是嘛
Yes, I suppose you have.
‎谢谢
Well, thank you.
我在努力了
I'm working on it.
‎你知道我要说什么
You know what I'm going to say.
‎快点干
Work faster.
‎是的
Yes.
‎是的 但是也要尽善尽美
Yes, but it needs to be perfect,
‎否则什么都做不出来
or nothing will come out of the end.
‎你真讨厌
Ugh, you're disgusting.
‎赫克托做出该死的锤子了吗
Has Hector made his fucking hammer yet?
‎他还在努力
He's still working on it.
‎他在拖延时间
He's stalling.
‎他很单纯 不会那样干的
He's too simple for that.
‎-不是  ‎-不是吗
- No. - No?
‎不是
No.
‎他身上有狡猾的气息
There's a deviousness in him.
‎你竟然怀疑布娃娃
Would you suspect a rag doll
打算偷你的钱包吗
of planning to steal your coin purse?
‎你误以为那只小狗温顺愚蠢
You mistake that puppy thing for being placid and stupid.
‎他能杀人
He can kill.
‎他试过一次
He tried, once.
‎充其量是不情愿
It was half-hearted at best.
‎看到了吗
Mm. See?
‎看到什么 你当时不在场
See what? You weren't there.
‎他很困惑 也很害怕
He was confused and frightened,
‎几乎不知道自己在做什么
and barely even knew what he was doing.
‎我是在提醒你
I'm warning you.
‎好吗
All right?
‎我只是提醒你
I'm just warning you.
‎拜托 如果他这么危险 ‎德古拉会把他
Please, would Dracula have kept him around in his own castle
‎留在自己的城堡里吗
if he were that dangerous?
‎我本来很喜欢那座城堡
I would have liked that castle.
‎德古拉的城堡吗
Dracula's castle?
‎是的
Yes.
‎我没怎么看过那座城堡
I didn't see a lot of it, in the end.
‎但我肯定里面
But I'm sure it was full
满是有趣奇妙的东西
of interesting and wonderful things.
‎我必须得指出来 ‎你已经有一座漂亮的城堡了
I am compelled to point out that you already have a nice castle.
‎为什么想要他的城堡
Why would you want his?
‎因为我从愚蠢邪恶的老头手里抢东西
Because I take things away from stupid, evil old men.
‎我就是干这个的
It's what I do.
‎我一直都这么干
I've always done it.
‎他们活该失去一切
They deserve to lose everything.
‎而我应该拥有他们所有的东西
And I deserve to have all their stuff.
‎你可以创造新的东西
You could just make new things.
‎如果我能抢走自己想要的东西
Why would I waste my time,
‎然后杀了拥有这些东西的人
when I can just take whatever I want
‎为什么还要浪费时间自己创造
and then kill whoever had them?
‎看看我的地图
Look at my map.
‎从这里到布勒伊拉
From here to Braila.
‎那片土地和村镇属于老头
That land and those villages and towns belong to old men.
‎全都是
All of them.
‎我要把它们抢过来
And I'm going to take them.
‎这座城堡曾经属于 ‎一个愚蠢邪恶的老头
This castle belonged to a stupid, evil old man.
‎我抢过来了
I took it.
‎从这里到布勒伊拉的土地
The land from here to Braila,
‎曾经掌控在愚蠢的老头手里
ruled by stupid old men.
‎毁在一个愚蠢的老头手里
Devastated by one single stupid old man.
‎等着你下手
There for the taking.
‎你全抢过来就会开心吗
And will you be happy when you have all that?
‎看看这个
Just look at this.
‎你看
Look.
‎你知道有多少地区的‎吸血鬼统治者死在布勒伊拉吗
Do you know how many regional vampire rulers died at Braila?
‎我不知道我还要数人头
I didn't know I had to count them.
‎那你应该数一下
Well, you should.
‎真不少
It was a lot.
‎这些只是我确定的数目
These are just the ones I'm certain of.
‎这些小旗子吗
These little flags?
‎没错
That's right.
‎所有这些没有吸血鬼直接统治的地区
All these regions without direct vampire rule.
‎只等着有人来掌控
Just waiting for someone to take control.
‎他们的臣民肯定会推举一个人来统治
Surely their underlings will raise someone up into command.
‎除非我们先下手为强
Unless we were there first.
‎我们为什么要这么做
Why would we do that?
‎这可是全世界 丽诺尔
This is the world, Lenore.
‎我们可以把全世界占为己有
We could take the entire world for our own.
‎你不想这样吗
Wouldn't you want that?
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎装天真可爱这招对我可没用 丽诺尔
The "sweet little girl" act doesn't work on me, Lenore.
‎再说一次
Try again.
‎我真的不知道
I really don't know.
‎我...我从来没有想过这么大的计划
I...I never thought about anything that big before.
‎那就开始想吧
Start.
‎先回答我的问题
Answer my question first.
‎拥有这一切
Will you be happy
你会开心吗
when you have all this?
‎我人生的开端是男人夺走我的东西
The first part of my life was men taking things from me.
‎然后我夺去他们的性命
And then I took their lives.
夺走他们的东西
And their things.
‎占领他们的家园
And their homes.
‎然后我们占领了施第里尔
And then we took Styria.
‎后来 我们打造自己的小领地
After which we formed our little enclave.
‎我们尽量不造成更大的伤害
We tried not to do more harm.
‎我们努力建设家园
We tried to make a home.
‎然后狼人从北边打来
And when the wolf people came from the north,
‎大军从西边进攻
and the armies from the west,
‎所有的混蛋都来攻击我们
and every other bastard came for us.
‎我们请求援助
And we asked for help.
‎吸血鬼世界的其他人当时怎么说的
What did the rest of the vampire world say?
‎他们说 "该死的女人"
"Bloody women," they said.
‎他们说 "让她们去死"
"Let them die," they said.
‎所以我要夺走所有人的一切
So I'm going to take everything from everybody.
‎我去过德古拉的城堡
I was in Dracula's castle.
‎我去那里 是看我能从中得到什么
I went there to see what I could get out of it.
‎让自己拥有更多力量
Get some more power for myself.
‎为我们带来更多保障
Some more security for us.
‎我发现他和手下搞砸了
What I found was him and his people just fucking it up.
‎我在那里看到
And I saw, right there,
‎我可以从他手里夺走全世界
that I could take the world away from him
并据为己有
and have it for myself!
‎全世界 丽诺尔
The world, Lenore!
‎我成功之后会开心吗
Will I be happy when I've done that?
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎我不知道我是否在乎
I don't know if I even care.
‎但我会拥有他们拥有的一切
But I will have everything that they had.
‎他们全都会死
And they will all be dead.
‎我会拥有我想要的全世界 ‎丽诺尔
I will have the world I want, Lenore,
而这...
and that...
‎这就够了
that will be enough.
‎拥有一切就够了
Having everything will be enough.
‎拥有全世界
Having the world.
‎他们全都死了
And all of them being dead.
‎一切都是为了这个吗
Is this what it was all for?
‎你觉得这是为了什么
What on earth did you think this was all about?
‎我想 他的锤子做好了
I think he finished his hammer.
‎好吧 在这里住一晚上
Well, this won't be terrible,
也不算糟糕
for one night.
‎你看 甚至还有‎迷人的窗户呢
Look, it's even got an attractive window.
在屋顶上
In the roof.
‎好极了 睡在星光下
Perfect. Sleeping under starlight.
‎还会被鸟屎砸中
And targeted by bird shit.
‎从我们到这里 我就没见过一只鸟
I haven't seen a single bird since we got here.
‎真的吗
Really?
‎我能听到房梁上有动静
I can hear something up in the rafters.
‎该死
Oh, shit.
‎又来了
Here we go again.
‎尽量别把谷仓烧了
Try not to burn the barn down
我们还在里面呢
while we're in it.
‎我只失手烧过一次
I did that one time.
‎一次就够了
One time was enough.
‎上次有一只大蜘蛛
It had a giant spider in it.
‎不是很大
It wasn't giant.
‎三米高啊
It was ten feet tall.
‎也许才两米五
Maybe eight.
‎所以呢 两米五的蜘蛛难道不算大吗
So, what, eight feet tall isn't giant?
妈的
Fuck me.
‎又是这些混蛋
These bastards again.
‎他们很厉害 不是吗
They're very good, aren't they?
‎他们很烦人
They're annoying.
‎也很年轻
And young.
算是吧
I suppose.
‎很漂亮
Pretty.
‎皮肤光滑
Smooth skin.
‎怎么 你想下去为他们主持婚礼吗
What, did you want to nip down there and marry them?
‎我想披上他们的皮
I want to wear their skin.
‎你确定不想让我放火吗
Are you sure you don't want me to set fire to things?
‎我现在觉得放火也许是个办法
I'm thinking it might be an option now.
‎谢谢
Thanks.
‎我们不知怎么掉进了这个圈套
We somehow managed to walk right into that one.
‎不是冲你们来的 ‎这是给我们设的陷阱
It wasn't for you. The trap was for us.
‎我是特雷弗·贝尔蒙特
I'm Trevor Belmont.
‎这是赛珐·贝尔纳德斯
This is Sypha Belnades.
‎扎姆菲尔 塔哥维斯特地下宫廷的警卫队长
Zamfir. Head guard to the Underground Court of Targoviste.
‎什么
The what?
‎德古拉第一次袭击后
The ruling family of Targoviste
‎塔哥维斯特王室活了下来
survived Dracula's first assault.
‎但后来吸血鬼和黑暗生物来了
But, later, the vampires and night creatures came,
‎为了安全起见
and it was safer to move them
‎他们躲进了城市地下的洞穴里
into the catacombs under the city.
‎我很惊讶还有人活着
I'm amazed anyone's still alive,
更别说王室了
let alone the royal family.
‎我带领抵抗运动对抗恶魔
I run the resistance against the devils.
‎地狱也试图诅咒我们的黄金城
Hell itself has attempted to curse our golden city,
‎但我们不会屈服
but we will not allow it.
‎我为你的手下感到遗憾
I'm sorry about your people.
‎我们感谢你的帮助
We are grateful for your aid.
‎他们是为王室而死
They died for the Court.
‎他们确实是死了
Well, they did die.
‎他们是你的朋友 不是吗
They were your friends, were they not?
‎我们一直在追查让德古拉
We have been following signs of some plot
‎起死回生的阴谋迹象
to return Dracula to Earth.
你了解这个情况吗
Does this mean anything to you?
‎城里有很多吸血鬼想这样做
There's a nest of vampires in the city who wish it.
‎他们想找到地下宫廷
They are trying to find the Underground Court,
‎掠夺数量众多的魔法宝藏 ‎用于他们的事业
to ransack its many magical treasures for their cause.
‎我们有兴趣参观这个宫廷
We would be interested in seeing this court.
‎以铲除这个隐患
To evaluate the threat.
‎我们很高兴
We would be delighted
你们加入王室的战斗
to have you join the royal struggle.
‎很好
Well, good.
‎帮助我们拯救塔哥维斯特
Help us save Targoviste.
‎很乐意
Gladly.
‎但现在还不行
But not yet.
‎等我确定可以信任你们
I cannot take you to the court
‎才能带你们进入宫廷
until I am certain I can trust you.
‎该死
Oh, shit.
‎她...很有意思
Well, she was... interesting.
‎你是说 有点疯狂吧
You mean a little crazy.
‎没错
Oh, yes.
‎可怜的家伙
You poor bastards.
‎-你在做什么 ‎-没什么
- What are you doing? - Nothing.
‎我知道你不会发死人财
Oh, I know you're not robbing the dead.
‎绝对不会
Absolutely not.
‎我已经看够发光的石头了
And I've seen enough glowing rocks for a while.
它们只会带来麻烦
They lead to trouble.
‎说得很对
Quite right too.
为什么要惹麻烦
Why invite trouble?
‎我们从不惹麻烦
We never do that.